

Personal **Profile**

Academic Interest

Mixed Reality

Serious Games

Data visualisation

3D Art & Design

Independent, proactive and able to play different roles within project, I have a deep affinity with utilizing data to design virtual reality games. I am keen to use data visualization to creatively design with advanced technology and new means of expression to equip digital experience with low-threshold, publicity, affinity and inspiration. I possess the skill sets (e.g. data visualization programming, 3D modeling, scene building, animation, game engine development, etc.) to generate, develop, and evaluate novel VR games with aesthetics and value.

Education

The University of Edinburgh

2021-2022 Edinburgh, UK

Master of Art in Design Informatics

GPA:70/100 | Dissertation 78/100 | Class of award with merit

Shanghai University

2018-2021

Shanghai, China

Master of Philosophy in Design

GPA:84/100 | First-class Professional Scholarship(2018) Second-class Professional Scholarship (2019, 2020)

Tianjin University of Technology

2014-2018 Tianjin, China

Bachelor of Arts in Visual Communication Design

GPA:3.6/4.0 | First-class, The People's Scholarship in China **Graduation with Honours & Excellent Graduation Thesis**

Project Experience

AR Finance Partner: Designing for Assisting Financial Decision-Making

05/2022 - 08/2022 Augmented Reality

Fintech Financial Literacy

- · Designed an AR headset-based application for financial management skills reinforcement and education, with the aim of improving Chinese young adults' confusion and increasing their capability in financial management during their transition from school to society.
- Conducted 20 semi-structured interviews and 2 co-design workshops based on the research question of how designers can improve financial literacy among Chinese young adults.
- Created prototypes on AR headsets utilizing user insights from interviews. Organised Kano analytics to communicate user tasks and usability tests for user flows and interactions.

Falling Manna: 3D Virtual Reality Game to Promote Self-tracking of Diet Data and Scottish Foods

09/2021-12/2022 Virtual Reality Data Visualization Unity 3D

- · Designed an educational virtual reality game with the theme of personal diet and calorie monitoring for Scotland residents. Designed and shipped an educational, playable and inspiring gaming experience.
- · Built vision, game UI assets, virtual assets, ran user research, and defined game framework and experience blueprint, using animated and VR prototypes with Figma, After Effects and Unity 3D.
- · Collaborated with creative engineers in Unity 3D and Oculus VR environment, support game object inputs and management.

Transfiguration

11/2021

Augmented Reality

Virtual Garment

- Co-created an art installation called Transfiguration, a transformable dress and a mirror reflecting virtual garment, supported by the expertise of the School of Engineering at the University of Edinburgh.
- The project was exhibited at the Soft Robotics International Conference.

Work

Xianda College of Economics & Humanities, Shanghai International Studies University

Experience

05/2023-Present Lecturer, Digital Media Arts

- · Courses taught include "Virtual Interactive Art Design", "Game Special Effects Design and Engine Basic Practice", "Game UI Graphic Design".
- Practiced teaching methods with virtual space display techniques in collaboration with the environmental art design subject group.

Academy of Arts and Design, Tsinghua University

12/2022-03/2023 MetaVerse Designer Internship

- · Participated in the design of the future knowledge planet, responsible for data collection, content scenario building and post-model optimization for digital spaces, with cloud classrooms and space stations included.
- · Enabled knowledge exchange and interaction between experiencers in a digital capacity through interaction design.

Shanghai Academy of Fine Arts (SHAFA), Shanghai University

09/2019-06/2021 Teaching Assistant & Coordinator

- · Tutored undergraduate students of Design, assisting for assignments, assessments, and final grades collection.
- · Coordinated for the lectures of SHAFA Forum, including airport pick-up and accommodation arrangement for the lecturers, and maintaining order at the forum.

Shanghai Ipsos Information Technology Co., Ltd. Shanghai, China

06/2020-09/2020 User Interface Designer

- Assisted data analysts in information design.
- · Participated in the interface design and interaction design of the big data analysis platform of BMW, GM, and Geely automobile brands, such as BMW's model billboard, image detection module, Geely's Lynk & Co model billboard, and GM's nebula graph for market competition pattern.

Awards &

Essay: AR Finance Partner - Designing for Assisting Financial Decision Making

Publications

12/2023 Contributions in progress Dissertation

Essay: Grayscale design and balance of text messages

09/2020

Journal of Nanjing Art Institute (Chinese Social Sciences Citation Index)

Essay: Shanghai Printing Technology Research Institute Text Font Design in A Collection of Words

09/2019 **Published on Sinogram Culture**

Excellence Award, 2017 The 9th National Advertising Art Design Competition For College Students

09/2017 Chinese Association of Higher Education (CAHE)

Certificates

National Senior High School Teacher Qualification Certificate

Skills

Design Tools

Cinema 4D, Blender, Figma, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Premiere, Sketch

Design Methods

User research, Market research, Cultural probes, Personas, Mapping journeys, Storyboard, Wireframing

Prototyping

Unreal Engine, Unity Engine, C#, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript